# Evgen Vittsenko

# Frontend Developer

### Contacts

Ukraine (remote)

+380678043844

yevhenvittsenko@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com

@EvgenVittsenko

# **Tech Skills**

• HTML | CSS | SCSS

- BEM | Adaptive & responsive web design
- Flexbox | Grid layout
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- Vue.js | Nuxt.js
- Vuex | Pinia
- Vue router | Vuetify
- Vue CLI, Vite
- ESLint
- Rest API | Fetch | Axios
- Git, GitLab | Figma | VS code | Webstorm
- Linux, Jira, Trello
- Webflow

### Soft Skills

- Strong sense of responsibility and ownership over tasks
- Good analytical and communication skills
- Transparent and honest communication

### Education

# Participant of the mentoring program from Beetroot Academy

Nov 2022 - Mar 2023

Beetroot Academy Front-End Developing

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

Zaporizhzhia National Technical University

Faculty of transport, Organization of transportation

# Languages

**Ukrainian:** Native

English: Pre-Intermediate (A2)

# Summary

I have almost 2 years of commercial experience in Frontend development, during which I have worked extensively with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Vue.js/Nuxt.js framework. I specialise in developing projects of various sizes, focusing on creating new landing pages and components, implementing the necessary logic and functionality, and working with existing codebases. During the development of landing pages:

- optimized the development process, increasing speed by 50%
- developed a landing page that improved conversion rates by 20%

I worked on projects related to a social networking platform and a financial platform (fintech).

During the development of a financial platform:

- took full responsibility for the frontend development
- led a full platform redesign, which contributed to attracting investors
- rewrote the routing system, significantly improving platform performance

In my chosen field, I find inspiration in the opportunity to continually develop and refine my skills, ultimately aiming to deliver maximum value to the business.

### Portfolio

Link to my portfolio-site:

https://yevhen0905.github.io/portfolio/

# **Professional Experience**

### Frontend Developer at DDI Development

June 2024 - present

### Key responsibilities:

- development of new components on the project, work with the existing code base, adaptive layout
- creating new product functionality and features using **Vue.js**
- fix bugs, code refactoring, optimization
- collaborate with various functional departments to deliver client solutions, from initial discussions to implementation

### Frontend Developer at UNIMO

Aug 2023 - April 2024

### Key responsibilities:

- development of new landing pages, editing, adaptive layout
- creating new features and capabilities on the site using Vue.js, Nuxt.js
- fix bugs, code refactoring, optimization
- collaborating with developers, Ui/Ux designer

### Frontend Developer, Self-employed

Mar 2023 - July 2023

### Key responsibilities:

• improvement of professional skills, creation of pet projects using JavaScript, Vue.js (view portfolio above)

### **Previous Career**

# Leading specialist, Logistics manager

"ADMIRAL LOGISTICS" LLC,
"ASKO EXPEDITION" LLC,
ZAZ Automobile Plant

### Experience gained:

- planning work processes, introduction of negotiations
- the ability to work with a large amount of information and to complete tasks in a stipulated time
- full information support of all transport processes
- document flow control, conclusion of contracts